Guide to the Oregon State University Extension Association/4-H Records 1977-1996
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
Oregon State University Extension Association/4-H Records
1977-1996
1980-1992
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center Special Collections & University Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://archives.library.oregonstate.edu
MSS OSUEA4H
Oregon State University Extension Association/4-H
0.7 cubic feet, including 622 photographs and 1 audiocassette 3 boxes
The Oregon State University Extension Association/4-H Records document the members, programs, and activities of the professional association of 4-H extension agents in Oregon. The organization was established in 1975 and is affiliated with the National Association of Extension 4-H Agents (NAE4-HA) and the Oregon State University Extension Association.
Historical Note:
The Oregon State University Extension Association/4-H (OSUEA/4-H) is the professional association of extension workers, mostly extension agents, who work with the 4-H/Youth program in Oregon. Prior to 1986, the organization was known as the Oregon Extension Association/4-H (OEA/4-H). OSUEA/4-H is affiliated with the National Association of Extension 4-H Agents (NAE4-HA). OSUEA/4-H was organized in 1975 and in 1977 placed a bid to host the 1983 NAE4-HA Conference in Portland, Oregon. A full history of the organization is available in the collection.
The Oregon State University Extension Association/4-H (OSUEA/4-H) Records document the membership, programs, and activities of the professional organization for 4-H Extension Agents in Oregon. In addition to administrative records of the OSEA/4-H, the collection includes substantive materials pertaining to the National Association of Extension 4-H Agents (NAE4-HA) 1983 Conference in Portland, Oregon, that was hosted and sponsored by the Oregon affiliate. The collection includes 622 photographs (color slides and color prints). The bulk of the photographs are of the 1983 national conference; other images depict the participation of Oregon members at the Oregon and national conferences in other years. The photographs also include a slide-tape program prepared to promote the 1983 conference. A name index of conference attendees shown in the prints is available with the collection.
Collection is open for research.
The Records are arranged in 15 series: I. Budgets and Treasurer's Reports, 1987-1992; II. Committees, 1990-1991; III. Correspondence, 1992; IV. Professional Improvement Conference, 1991; V. Historical Documents, 1989-1990; VI. Rules of Operation - Bylaws, 1980-1989; VII. Minutes, 1980-1992; VIII. Newsletter, 1988-1991; XI. Membership Lists, 1977-1991; X. Handbooks, 1986-1991; XI. Survey, 1986; XII. National Association of Extension 4-H Agents (NAE4-HA), 1980-1986; XIII. NAE4-HA 1983 Conference, Rainbows and Roses, 1980-1984; XIV. Photographs, 1979-1996; and XV. Sound Recording, 1983.
The records were transferred to the University Archives in several accessions from 1990 thru 1997.
The Special Collections & Archives Research Center provides access to many collections documenting the 4-H and Youth Program in Oregon including the Extension Service Records (RG 111); the 4-H Photograph Collection (P 146) and Moving Images (FV P 146); the OSU Extension Service Faculty and Staff Oral History collection (OH 14); and the papers of several 4-H leaders including Roberta Frasier Anderson, James F. Bishop, Helen Cowgill, and Esther Taskerud. The Center's collections also include the Oregon State University Extension Association (OSEA) Records, the Malheur County 4-H Leaders' Council Records, and the N. John Hansen Scrapbook.
National Association of Extension 4-H Agents.; National Association of Extension 4-H Agents.; Oregon State University. Extension Service.; Oregon State University--Faculty.
Agricultural extension workers--Oregon.; County agricultural agents--Oregon.; 4-H clubs--Oregon.; Home economics extension workers--Oregon.; Youth--Oregon--Societies and clubs.
Portland (Or.)
Audiocassettes.; Photographic prints.; Slides.
Children and Youth; Colleges and Universities; Women; Oregon; Corvallis; Portland; Artifacts; Photographs; Sound Recordings
- Budgets and Treasurer's Reports, 1987-1992; Series I (Box 1)
  Series I documents the financial status of the Association, including annual reports of income and expenses and account balances.
- Committees, 1990-1991; Series II (Box 1)
  Series II includes lists of committee members as well as committee reports and proposals.
- Correspondence, 1992; Series III (Box 1)
  Series III consists of a letter from the OSUEA/4-H President, Pamela Olsen, to OSU Extension Director, O.E. Simpson, regarding a professional exchange program.
- Professional Improvement Conference, 1991; Series IV (Box 1)
  Series IV provides information on the Professional Improvement Conference held in Bend in 1991.
- Historical Documents, 1989-1990; Series V (Box 1)
  Series V includes summaries of the history of the OSUEA/4-H organization and recognition of Oregon 4-H Agents by the national organization prior to the establishment of the Oregon affiliate.
- Rules of Operation - Bylaws, 1980-1989; Series VI (Box 1)
  Series VI includes the constitution, bylaws, and rules of operation for the organization.
- Minutes, 1980-1992; Series VII (Box 1)
  Series VII includes minutes and agendas for the Executive Committee, Board, and Annual Business Meeting of the organization. These includes reports from committees and officers as well as summaries of programs and activities.
- Newsletter, 1988-1991; Series VIII (Box 1)
  Series VIII consists of the organization's newsletter, News 'n Notes, which was issued several times per year.
- Membership Lists, 1977-1991; Series IX (Box 1)
  Series IX includes lists of members of the OSUEA/4-H as well as Oregon members of the NAE4-HA. Several of the lists indicate the county in which the 4-H Agent was working at the time. Lists of OSUEA/4-H officers are also included.
- Handbooks, 1986-1991; Series X (Box 1)
  Series X consists of an OSUEA/4-H handbook (1991) with information about the organization for the membership and a handbook for state associations prepared by the National Association of Extension 4-H Agents (NAE4-HA) in 1986.
- Survey, 1986; Series XI (Box 1)
  Series XI documents a survey of the membership conducted in 1986 to identify potential leaders and future program needs.
- National Association of Extension 4-H Agents (NAE4-HA), 1980-1986; Series XII
  Series XII consists of two issues of the NAE4-HA newsletter, including the 40th anniversary issue (November 1986), and campaign materials (including buttons) for Oregon members seeking national office.
  - News & Views, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
  - Oregon members' campaigns, 1980-1984 (Box 1)
- NAE4-HA 1983 Conference, Rainbows and Roses, 1980-1984; Series XIII; 3 folders (Box 1)
  Series XIII documents planning and preparation for and hosting of the 1983 national conference by OSUEA/4-H in Portland and includes programs, a final report, information about tours and donors, bid materials, guidelines, committee records, correspondence, planning calendars, budgets and financial documents, thank you notes and letters, and ephemera (suspenders and buttons).
- Photographs, 1979-1996; Series XIV
  Series XIV consists of color slides (304) and color prints (318) primarily documenting Association conferences, including attendees, speakers, poster presentations, award ceremonies, and special events. The bulk of the color prints are from the 1983 national conference held in Portland, Oregon. The series also include promotional slides for the 1983 conference.
  - Slide-Tape Program Promoting 1983 Conference, 208 color slides (Box 2)
    Primarily views of Oregon and Portland scenes and activities. Also includes some images of conference and 4-H activities.
  - Conferences, 1979-1996; 318 color prints
    These images document attendees, speakers, exhibits, award presentations, and special events at the Association's conferences. The bulk of the images are for the 1983 national conference that was held in Portland, Oregon. A name index is included with the photographs. The following individuals are depicted: John Baggott, Dick Best, Marjorie Brock, Bill Broderick, Suzi Busler, Steve Campbell, Caroline Cannon, Cheri Jo Carter, Barbara Christy, Helen Conner, Pat Coolican, Paula Dance, Patricia Dawson, Jim Douglas, Linda Ericksen, Sally Francis, Dale Friedeman, Lois Goering, Norm Goetze, Mary Ann Greeland, Roy Hamilton, Wendy Hamilton, Doug Hart, Beverly Hobbs, Maureen Hosty, Lyla Houglum, Elaine Husted, Duane Johnson, Alberta Johnston, Joy Jones, Harold Kerr, Ken Killingsworth, Carol Knothe, Ardis Koester, Karen Lang, Lillian Larwood, Miriam Lowrie, Bill Maddy, Ann Manlove, Mollie Marsh, Dan McGrath, Mitchell Gregg, Betty Morrison, Ira Mumford, Pamela Olsen, Jeff Olsen, Shelly Pagel, Jan Pahl, Terry Palmer, Clay Penhollow, Christy Price, Michelle Robinson, Dora Rumsey, Jim Rutledge, Bob Salzer, Barb Sawer, Ann Schauber, Sally Shumway, Tammy Skubinna, Ed Slocum, Bill Smiley, Janice (Broome) Smiley, Ernie Smith, Alan Snider, Lyle Speichert, Garry Stephenson, Billie Stevens, Mary Stewart, Marcelle Straatman, Mary Ann Sward, Frances Torbeck, Brain Tuck, Betty Wallace, Chris Warburton, Sandy Watts, and Shana Withee.
    - 1979, 1 color print (Box 2)
    - Identified Oregon Extension Faculty Members (section 1), 1983; 53 color prints (Box 2)
    - Identified Conference Attendees (section 2), 1983; 56 color prints (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Attendees (section 3), 1983; 146 color prints (Box 2)
    - 1987, 1 color print (Box 2)
    - 1989, 16 color prints (Box 2)
    - 1990, 4 color prints (Box 2)
    - 1995, 21 color prints (Box 2)
    - 1996, 20 color prints (Box 2)
  - Conferences, 1987-1989; 96 color slides (Box 2)
    These photographs depict speakers, poster presentations, meetings, and activities at OSUEA/4-H and national conferences, including the NAE 4-HA conference in Mobile, Alabama, in 1989.
- Sound Recording, 1983; Series XV (Box 3)
  Series XV consists of an audiocassette tape for a slide-tape program promoting the national NAE4-HA conference held in Portland in 1983.